DAVID I OUIF **FULLSTACK WEB** DEVELOPER

Contact

- dlouie1492@gmail.com
- dthelouie.github.io
- 3478044263
- New York, NY

https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidlouie-67332357

O dthelouie

Skills

LANGUAGES

Ruby

JavaScript (jQuery, AJAX)

DATABASES

ActiveRecord

SQL

WEB FRAMEWORKS

Rails

Sinatra

METHODOLOGIES

Object-Oriented Design

MVC Struture

RESTful Design

Agile Development

FRONT END

HTMI 5

C553

VERSION CONTROL

GitHub

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT KITS

Xcode

SOFTWARF

Final Cut Pro X

Adobe Photoshop

Microsoft Office

GarageBand

Above any occupation I may assume, I am a student, and I will always be a student. I feel like I'm constantly learning wherever I am. Through my experience in college, I gained a true understanding of my own metacognitive learning abilities. Through my work with community organizations, I have learned the importance of strong communication skills across different contexts and platforms. With Dev Bootcamp, I learned how to use Javascript and Ruby on Rails to make Web apps, and applied that learning process to Swift. With this, I was able to develop an app with my team in just 5 days. And as a Web developer, I love that I will constantly expand on my skillset and apply what I've learned to new picking up new languages and technologies.

Projects

Carrot-App

Source Code: https://github.com/dthelouie/Carrot-App

Carrot-App is an iOS application built in Xcode with Swift that helps you avoid social faux pas when it comes to eating your carrots. It uses your device's microphone and actively surveys the noise level of the room that you're in to tell you whether or not you can eat your carrots without disturbing the people around you.

- Built over 5 days with no prior knowledge of Swift
- Makes use of Apple's AVFoundation and CGAffine frameworks
- Uses device microphone to measure the room for an average power level in decibels
- Gives a prompt for the appropriate action by comparing the room's average power level to that of the bite of a carrot

Survey Code Monkey Gorillas

Source Code: https://github.com/nyc-squirrels-2016/survey-code-monkey-gorillas

A simple survey site with users that can create and take surveys.

- Implemented token system to give creators the ability to control who takes their surveys
- Tokens limit unregistered users to taking any given survey only once

Stack Flow-no-mo

Source Code: https://github.com/nyc-squirrels-2016/stack-flow-no-mo

A site where users can post questions that can be answered by other users.

- Questions and answers can be commented and voted on
- Users must be logged in to participate in posting of any kind

A 2048 Clone.

Live Link: http://dthelouie.github.io/projects/2048-clone/index.html

Source Code: https://github.com/dthelouie/256-challenge

A game in which the player combines powers of 2 to make higher numbers, with the goal of reaching 2048 and beyond.

- Done in JavaScript, with UnderScore.js and jQuery

Employment

Baruch College Summer Camp

New York, NY, 10010 Jul 2013 to Aug 2013, Jul 2014 to Aug 2014, Jul 2015 to Aug 2015

Port Jefferson, NY, 11777

Baruch College Summer Camp is held every summer. Since most of the children that attend camp either live near the campus or have parents working in the building, this program gives parents a safe place to leave their children while they work during the day.

- Ensure the safety of children age 4 to 14 during camp activities such as swimming, gym, arts & crafts, and computers.
- Consistently liaise and communicate with parents to address the specific needs of their children

Greater Port Jefferson Arts Council

Sep 2014 to Oct 2014 Twice a year, the Greater Port Jefferson Arts Council hosts a 6 week documentary series, during which, once a week there will be a

documentary covering various topics screened for the public to enjoy.

- Handled the retrieval and transport of sound equipment for the Port Jefferson Documentary Series
- Managed the setup and operation of equipment during weekly documentary screening
- Facilitated Q&A sessions with directors of the featured film and the attending audience

Education

Dev Bootcamp is a 19 week immersive web development program. Students go from being programming novices to fullstack developers by being taught the fundamentals of object oriented programming, model view controller structure, and web frameworks such as Sinatra and Rails.

Stony Brook University B.A. Economics 2014 Minor Music 2014

Stony Brook University is a branch of the State University of New York, and is located on Long Island.